dailygrommet.com 2019-12-23

# Privacy Policy | The Grommet®

Last updated March 15, 2018

## What This Privacy Policy Covers

* * *

The Grommet values your privacy. This notice describes what information we collect, how we use it, and, if necessary, those with whom we share it. By visiting The Grommet, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. Your use of the Website is also subject to our Terms of Use, available at [Terms of Use](https://www.thegrommet.com/terms-of-use).

## Types of Information Gathered

* * *

The information we learn from customers helps personalize and continually improve your shopping experience at The Grommet. Here are the types of information we gather:

You provide information when you search, watch, buy, post, participate in a contest, subscribe to Grommet email, suggest a potential Grommet, or communicate with customer service. As a result of those actions, you might supply us with such personally identifiable information as your name, address, and phone number(s); email address(es); credit card information; and content of your comments about or opinions of Grommets. We use the information that you provide for such purposes as responding to your requests, processing your order, selecting new Grommets and/or products and services and serving you relevant advertising. The Grommet will not collect any personally identifiable information about you unless you provide it.

Like many websites, we use "cookies." We obtain certain types of anonymous information which is not personally identifiable when your web browser accesses The Grommet or third party content (such as our Widget) served by or on behalf of The Grommet on other websites. Some of the information we collect and analyze includes the Internet protocol (IP) address; computer and connection information such as browser type, version, and connection speed; purchase history; and the products you searched for, viewed, and possibly purchased.

To help us make emails more useful and interesting, we often receive a confirmation when you open email from The Grommet and the products and/or links on which you click if your computer supports such capabilities.

Information from Other Sources

We might receive information about you from other sources and add it to our account information. For example, we receive updated delivery and address information from our carriers or other third parties, which we use to correct our records and deliver your next purchase or communication more easily.

## Cookies

* * *

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser for such purposes as to remember the items in your Shopping Cart between visits. The information collected from cookies may also be used to improve the functionality of the Website.

The Help portion of your web browser, most likely found on the toolbar, will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. However, because cookies allow you to take advantage of some of The Grommet's essential features, we recommend that you leave them turned on. For instance, if you block or otherwise reject our cookies, you will not be able to add items to your Shopping Cart, proceed to Checkout, or use any Grommet services that require you to Sign in.

## Pixel Tags and Tracking Technology

* * *

When you visit this Website or view one of our emails, we may use pixel tags (also called "clear" gifs), tracking links and/or similar technology to note some of the pages you visit on our Website and personalize your experience. We may also use pixel tags to determine what types of email your browser supports. We may use the information collected through pixel tags, tracking links and similar technology in combination with your personally identifiable information.

## How We Share Information

* * *

Information about our customers is an important part of our business, and we are not in the business of selling it to others. We share customer information only as described below.

When you place an order with The Grommet, a majority of the time the seller/manufacturer of the Grommet will fulfill the order. We send the supplier the order information including item(s) purchased, delivery address, billing address, and gifting information if part of the order. The order information we send to the supplier does not include your email address. From time to time, we may contact you on behalf of the supplier for customer service reasons such as to coordinating delivery times or if an item is out of stock. We will not provide your email address to any supplier without receiving your prior consent.

Third-Party Service Providers

We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, delivering packages, sending postal mail and email, email list management, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, providing search results and links (including paid listings and links), and processing credit card payments. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes.

We use third-party companies to help us serve targeted product recommendations. These companies may use data about you in order to provide recommendations for products and services that might be of interest to you. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit [networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). To opt out of Conversant remarketing, [click here](http://dtmc.thegrommet.com/adinfo/choice/prod/?type=fpc&cid=61808&cname=The%20Grommet&cmagic=7bb953&clogo=61808.png&loc=us&lang=en-us).

In the event that The Grommet creates, merges with, or is acquired by another entity, your information will most likely be transferred. The Grommet will email you or place a prominent notice on our Website before your information becomes subject to another privacy policy.

Protection of The Grommet and Others

We release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements, or protect the rights, property, or safety of The Grommet, our users or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

Other than as set out above, you will receive notice when personally identifiable information about you might go to third parties, and you will have an opportunity to choose not to share the information.

The Grommet uses the anonymous browsing information collected automatically by our servers primarily to help us administer and improve the Website. We may also use aggregated anonymous information to provide information about the Website to potential business partners and other unaffiliated entities. This information is not personally identifiable.

The email address that you supply to us for purposes of receiving our email communications will never be rented or sold to a third party.

## Protecting Your Information

* * *

We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input. If transactions are processed on the Website, transaction information is transmitted to and from the Website in encrypted form using industry-standard SSL connections to help protect such information from interception. Using this encryption, we transmit the entire credit card number to the appropriate credit card company during order processing but reveal only the last four digits of your credit card numbers when confirming an order. We restrict authorized access to your personal information to those persons who have a legitimate purpose to know that information to provide products or services to you and those persons you have authorized to have access to such information.

The Grommet follows generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once The Grommet receives it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while The Grommet strives to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Website, you can email The Grommet at [folks@thegrommet.com](mailto:folks@thegrommet.com)

## Editing and Deleting Account Information

* * *

You can change your Grommet Account Information at any time by logging into your account on the Website. To delete your account entirely, email your request to [folks@thegrommet.com](mailto:folks@thegrommet.com).

To opt-out of Grommet Email, follow the instructions included in the email. Your request should be processed within 48 hours.

## Suppliers and Other Third Parties

* * *

Except as otherwise expressly included in this Privacy Policy, this document addresses only the use and disclosure of information The Grommet collects from you. If you disclose your information to others, whether other users or suppliers on The Grommet, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of the information you disclose to them. The Grommet does not control the privacy policies of third parties, and you are subject to the privacy policies of those third parties where applicable. The Grommet is not responsible for the privacy or security practices of other websites on the Internet, even those linked to or from the The Grommet site. The Grommet encourages you to ask questions before you disclose your personal information to others.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

* * *

The Grommet will post modifications by date to this Privacy Policy to inform you of any changes. The Grommet reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, please review it frequently.

#### As featured in

The Grommet: 

The Birthplace of Citizen Commerce®

| 

87 Elmwood Street, Somerville, MA 02144

Copyright © 2012 - 2019. All rights reserved. For U.S. Residents Only
